(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-23T02:01:32.846540",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
今だからこそ、逆に昭和は、宝鐘マリン3周年記念企画！
Now more than ever, retro is in! Houshou Marine's 3rd Anniversary Project!
宝鐘マリン完全プロデュース、
Fully produced by Houshou Marine,
ホロライブ昭和歌謡祭！
Hololive Showa Kayou Festival!
バーチャル関東のホロライブスタジオよりお届けいたします。
Broadcasting live from Hololive Studio in Virtual Kanto.
今夜は昭和歌謡に酔い、大空スバルから火曜日に火曜曲を歌うアキ・ローゼンタールまで、
Tonight, intoxicated by Showa kayo, from Oozora Subaru to Aki Rosenthal singing Tuesday hits,
大勢のホロライブメンバーが、
A large lineup of Hololive members
昭和歌謡曲に挑戦！
Take on classic Showa songs!
存分に昭和のひとときをお楽しみください！
Please enjoy this wonderful Showa moment to your heart's content!
読み捨てられる雑誌のように
Like a magazine read once and thrown away,
私のページがめくれるたびに
Every time my page is turned,
放り出されてしまうのかしら
I wonder if I'll be cast aside.
それが知りたくて とても
I want to know so badly,
あなたの瞳の奥に
Deep inside your eyes,
旅してく わたしなの
I take a journey—that's me.
センチメンタル・ジャーニー
Sentimental Journey
つぼみのままで 夢を見たい
I want to keep dreaming like a flower bud,
影のように美しい 物語だけ見てたいわ
As beautiful as a shadow, wanting to watch only the story.
マリンはまだ17だから
Because Marine is still 17!
何かにさそわれて
Tempted by something,
あなたにさらわれて
Swept away by you...
センチメンタル・ジャーニー
Sentimental Journey
見知らぬ国の 謎の湖
A mysterious lake in an unknown land,
のぞきたくなる 不思議な気持ち
Such a strange feeling wanting to take a peek,
自分できさえも 怖いほどの
A love so intense it scares even me,
咲かせた恋なら ずっと
If it's a love I've bloomed,
大事にしていて 貰えるのかしら
I wonder if you'll treasure it forever?
判らない
I don't know.
センチメンタル・ジャーニー
Sentimental Journey
扉の前で ためらいながらも
Hesitating in front of the door,
背中をそっと 押されたい
Yet wanting my back gently pushed.
見ないふりして 許してね
Pretend you didn't see and forgive me.
マリンはまだ17だから
Marine is still 17,
何かにさそわれて あなたにさらわれて
Tempted by something, swept away by you...
センチメンタル・ジャーニー
A sentimental journey.
ラララ…
La la la...
1曲目は「センチメンタル・ジャーニー」をお聞きいただきました。
That was our first song, "Sentimental Journey."
原曲は「伊代はまだ16だから」を、マリンはまだ17だからと替え歌にしていたようですね。
The original goes "Iyo is still 16," but Marine changed it to "Marine is still 17."
いちまで17歳気分なんでしょうかね。宝鐘マリンは永遠に17歳です！
How long is she gonna keep up this 17-year-old vibe? Houshou Marine is forever 17!
お肌もまだピチピチです。
And her skin is still fresh and glowing.
はい。
Yes.
いやでも、マリンさん、まだまだ17歳としてはいけてる方なんじゃないでしょうか。
But still, Marine-san, aren't you doing pretty well as a 17-year-old?
そうなんですかね。でもちょっとあの、股関節が痛いみたいな聞いたことがありますけども。
Is that so? Though I've heard you mention something like your hip joints hurting...
そんな情報が…あったような気がします。
I feel like... there was info like that.
じゃあ股関節も大事にしていただいて、全身ピチピチの17歳でいてほしいですね。
Well, please take care of your hips and stay a vibrant 17-year-old all over!
そうですね。
Indeed.
それでは次の曲まいりましょう、どうぞ！
Now then, let's move on to the next song, here we go!
春色の汽車に乗って 海に連れて行ってよ
Take me on a spring-colored train down to the sea...
煙草の匂いのシャツに そっと寄りそうから
As I gently snuggle close to your cigarette-scented shirt.
何故知り合った日から 半年過ぎても あなたって手も握らない
Why is it, even half a year since we met, that you still won't even hold my hand?
I will follow you あなたにつれてゆきたい
I will follow you, I want to go with you...
I will follow you ちょっぴり気が弱いけど 素敵な人だから
I will follow you, because you're a wonderful person, even if you're a bit timid.
心の岸辺に咲いた 赤いスイートピー
A red sweet pea blooming on the shore of my heart.
四月の雨に降られて 駅のベンチで二人
Caught in the April rain, the two of us on the station bench,
他に人影もなくて 不意に気まずくなる
With no one else around, things suddenly get awkward.
何故あなたが時計を チラってみたび 泣きそうな気分になるの？
Why does every time you glance at your watch make me feel like I'm about to cry?
I will follow you 翼の生えたブーツで
I will follow you in winged boots...
あなたと同じ青春 走ってゆきたいの
I want to run through the same youth as you.
線路の脇のつぼみは 赤いスイートピー
The bud beside the railway tracks is a red sweet pea.
好きよ今日まで逢った誰より
I love you more than anyone I've ever met...
I will follow you あなたの生き方が好き このまま帰れない 帰れない
I will follow you, I love the way you live, I can't go home like this, I can't go home...
心に春が来た日は 赤いスイートピー
The day spring came into my heart, a red sweet pea.
二曲目は、大神ミオと赤いハートで『赤いスイートピー』をお聴きいただきました。
The second song was 'Akai Sweet Pea' performed by Ookami Mio and Akai Haato.
いやあ、二人ともすごく清楚でしたねえ。
Man, both of them were so pure and innocent.
そうですねえ、赤いさんでしたね。
That's right, they were Akai-san.
いや、赤いさんでした。
Yeah, Akai-san.
ま、昭和じゃまあではないですね。
Well, it's not the Showa era though.
誰ですか、その方は？ご存じありませんか？あ、そうですね。あ、そうですか。
Who is that person? You don't know? Ah, I see. Oh, is that so?
昭和の世界なのでね。あ、なるほど。ちゃんまは令和に生きております。
Since it's the Showa world. Ah, I see. Cham-ma lives in Reiwa.
あ、なるほど。『赤いスイートピー』はでも、あのアイドルソングらしくてとてもよかったですね。
Ah, I see. But 'Akai Sweet Pea' felt very much like an idol song and was really good.
そうですね。大神マリンは、『赤いスイートピー』のことを最初チューリップだと思ってたそうですね。
That's right. Houshou Marine apparently thought 'Akai Sweet Pea' was about tulips at first.
そうなんですか。全然違いますけどね。そうなんですけどね。
Is that so? It's completely different though. That's right.
それでは次の曲、まいりましょう。どうぞ！
Now then, let's move on to the next song. Here we go!
真赤なリンゴを頬ばる
Stuffs his mouth with a bright red apple
ネービーブルーのTシャツ
And wears a navy blue T-shirt
あいつはあいつはかわいい
He's a, he's a cute
年下の男の子
Younger boy
淋しがりやで
He's a loner,
生意気で
and a smart aleck,
にくらしいけど好きなの
and annoying, but I like him
LOVE 投げキッス
L-O-V-E, I blow a kiss
私のこと好きかしら
Does he like me?
はっきりきかせて
Tell me, and be nice and clear
ボタンのとれてるポケット
His pocket's missing a button
汚れてまるめたハンカチ
And his handkerchief is all balled up and dirty
あいつはあいつはかわいい
He's a, he's a cute
年下の男の子
Younger boy
デートの時間に遅れる
He's late to our dates
いつでもけんかをしかける
And he's always picking fights
あいつはあいつはかわいい
He's a, he's a cute
年下の男の子
Younger boy
忘れ坊で
He's forgetful,
わがままで
and selfish,
いじわるだけど好きなの
and mean, but I like him
LOVE 投げキッス
L-O-V-E, I blow a kiss
私のこと好きかしら
Does he like me?
はっきりきかせて
Tell me, and be nice and clear
片方なくした手袋
He's missing a glove
ほどけたまんまの靴ひも
And he leaves his shoes untied
あいつはあいつはかわいい
He's a, he's a cute
年下の男の子
Younger boy
淋しがりやで
He's a loner,
生意気で
and a smart aleck,
にくらしいけど好きなの
and annoying, but I like him
LOVE 投げキッス
L-O-V-E, I blow a kiss
私のこと好きかしら
Does he like me?
はっきりきかせて
Tell me, and be nice and clear
ボタンのとれてるポケット
His pocket's missing a button
汚れてまるめたハンカチ
And his handkerchief is all balled up and dirty
あいつはあいつはかわいい
He's a, he's a cute
年下の男の子
Younger boy
あいつはあいつはかわいい
He's a, he's a cute
年下の男の子
Younger boy
あいつはあいつはかわいい
He's a, he's a cute
年下の男の子
Younger boy
宝鐘マリン、秋色アンタール、柚子チョコで『年下の男の子』でした。
That was 'Toshishita no Otoko no Ko' by Houshou Marine, Aki Rosenthal, and Yuzuki Choco.
すごくお姉さんの3人でセクシーでしたね。
It was super sexy with three older sisters.
そうですね。こちらは秋色アンタールはやっぱりリンゴが歌詞に出てきますのでね。
That's right. Aki Rosenthal has apples appearing in the lyrics after all.
やはり年下の男の子といえばこの女ということで、柚子チョコさん。
And when talking about younger boys, this woman comes to mind—Yuzuki Choco-san.
ちょっとこう、タブーカしそうな感じが…
That's a bit revealing, isn't it?
あ、そうですね。
Ah, so it is.
なるほど。
I see.
この中に白金いろはさんもいたら、
And if Shirakami Iroha-san was in it too,
よりもうすごいなと思うんですけども、
I think it'd be even more amazing,
この後まだ出演が結構多数残っているということで、
but there are still quite a few appearances left,
多数？
Majority?
そうなんです。
That's right.
あ、そうなんですね。
Oh, is that so?
へえ。
I see.
その4人での歌唱もちょっと見てみたいですね。
I'd love to see the four-person cover too.
あ、そうですね。
Ah, yes.
ぜひ、あの、動画などお楽しみにしております。
Please look forward to the videos and such!
はい、それではお次まいりましょう。
Alright, then let's move on to the next one.
どうぞ！
Let's go!
秋が終わりば冬が来る
When fall ends, winter will be here,
ほんとに早いわ
it really goes by so fast.
夏休みには二人してサイパンへ行ったわ
Summer break, the two of us went to Saipan,
日焼けした肌まだ黒い
my tanned skin still dark,
楽しい思い出
a fun memory.
来年も又サイパンへ泳ぎに行きたいわ
Next year I wanna go swimming in Saipan again.
あなたは優しい人ね
You're such a nice person,
私を抱きよせてずっとこのままとKISSをした
embracing me and kissing me,
私がオバさんになっても泳ぎに連れてくの?
Will you take me swimming even when I'm a ma'am?
派手な水着はとてもムリよ
There's no way I'd wear a bright swimsuit,
若い子には負けるわ
the younger girls would have me beat.
私がオバさんになっても本当に変わらない?
Things really won't change even when I'm a ma'am?
とても心配だわあなたが若い子が好きだから
I worry about it because you like 'em young.
そんな話はバカげてるあなたは言うけど
You say talking about that kind of stuff is dumb,
女ざかりは19だといったのよ
you said yourself, girls peak at 19.
だけど何くわぬ顔で見つめて
But then you look at me innocently,
あれは冗談だったとKISSをした
and kiss me, saying it was a joke.
私がオバさんになってもディスコに連れてくの?
Will you take me to the disco even when I'm a ma'am?
ミニスカートはとてもムリよ若い子には負けるわ
There's no way I'd wear a mini-skirt, the younger girls would have me beat.
私がオバさんになってもドライブしてくれる?
Will you take me out on drives even when I'm a ma'am?
オープンカーの屋根はずしてかっこよく走ってよ
Put down the roof on your convertible and drive around looking cool.
私がオバさんになったらあなたはオジさんよ
When I'm a ma'am you'll be a sir,
かっこいいことばかりいってもお腹が出てくるのよ
even if all you ever say is cool stuff now, you'll have a dad gut then too.
私がオバさんになっても本当に変わらない?
Things really won't change even when I'm a ma'am?
とても心配だわあなたが若い子が好きだから
I worry about it because you like 'em young.
私がオバさんになってもでした。
and "Watashi ga Obasan ni Nattemo" was...
はい。
Yes!
すごくフレッシュで可愛らしかったですね。
It was super fresh and cute, wasn't it?
風間いろはさんの元気な姿がとても良くて、とてもフレッシュで良かったと思います。
Kazama Iroha-san's energetic look was so great, and it felt really fresh and wonderful.
2人ともとてもフレッシュでしたね。
Both of you were so fresh!
そうですね。
That's right.
はい。
Yes.
はい、とてもよかったと思います。
Yes, I think it was very good.
ちなみにみおさんはおばさんになったらどんなおばさんになりたいですか？
By the way, Mio-san, what kind of auntie do you want to be when you become one?
えっと、ポケットにアメちゃんが入ってるみたいなおばさんになりたいです。
Umm, I want to be an auntie who has hard candies in her pocket.
アメちゃん入ってる。
Hard candies in your pocket.
なるほど、はい、いいですね。優しいおばさんですね。
I see, yes, that's nice. A kind auntie.
フブキさんは80になってもゲームセンターに通うおばさんになりたいです。
Fubuki-san wants to be an auntie who goes to game centers even at 80.
ゲーセンおばあちゃんってことですね。
So, a game center grandma.
それでは次の曲まいりましょう、どうぞ。
Now let's move on to the next song, go ahead.
探しものは何ですか？
What are you looking for?
見つけにくいものですか？
Is it something hard to find?
カバンの中もつくえの中も探したけれど見つからないのに
I've searched inside my bag and in my desk, but I still can't find it.
まだまだ探す気ですか？
Do you still feel like searching?
それより僕と踊りませんか？
Instead, why don't you dance with me?
夢の中へ 夢の中へ
Into the dream, into the dream,
行ってみたいと思いませんか？
don't you want to try going there?
休む事も許されず
Not allowed to rest,
笑う事は止められて
not allowed to laugh,
はいつくばってはいつくばって いったい何を捜しているのか
crawling and crawling, what are you really searching for?
捜すのをやめた時 見つかることもある話で
It's often the case that when you stop searching, you find it.
踊りましょう夢の中へ
Let's dance, into the dream,
行ってみたいと思いませんか？
don't you want to try going there?
探しものは何ですか？
What are you looking for?
まだまだ探す気ですか？
Do you still feel like searching?
夢の中へ 夢の中へ
Into the dream, into the dream,
行ってみたいと思いませんか？
don't you want to try going there?
宝鐘マリン白銀ノエルで夢の中へでした。
That was "Yume no Naka e" by Houshou Marine and Shirogane Noel.
二人のハーモニーがとても気持ちよかったですね。
Their harmony felt very nice.
いやあすごくお耳が気持ちよくくなりましたね。
Yeah, our ears felt really good.
そうですね。
That's right.
ええこちらの選曲なんですけども、愛し彼女の事情というアニメの主題歌。
This song selection is the anime theme song "Aishi Kanojo no Jijou".
でたまたま聞いたところ昭和の曲だったということで選曲したそうです。
They chose it because it happened to be a Showa era song when they heard it.
そうですねリメイクの曲ですね。
That's right, it's a remake song.
そうですね良い曲でした。
That's right, it was a good song.
今回獅子白牡丹さんは、歌のコラボをしたことがないということでお誘いしてみたみたいです。
This time, since Shishiro Botan hadn't done a singing collab before, she seemed to have invited her.
いいハモリでしたね。
It was a good harmony.
ちなみに最近見た宝鐘マリンの夢なんですけども。
By the way, about Houshou Marine's dream she saw recently.
はい、ええなんか家の中に生えたきのこを食べたところ腹痛を起こしたという。
Yes, she ate mushrooms growing in her house and got a stomachache.
ああ大変ですね。
Oh, that's terrible.
ちょっと悲しい夢を見ていたそうです。
It seems she had a somewhat sad dream.
はいそれでは次の曲参りましょう。
Alright, let's move on to the next song.
Get up, Get up, Get up, Get up, Burning love
やり切れない程 退屈な時があるわ あなたと居ても
Sometimes I get so bored I can’t stand it, even when I’m with you
喋るぐらいなら踊っていたいの 今は 硝子のディスコティック
I might as well keep dancing if I’m going to talk about it, right now at the glass disco
そう みんな 堕天使ね
Yeah, everyone's a fallen angel
そう みんないずれも堕天使ね
Yeah, everyone's a fallen angel,
汗が羽の代わりに飛んでる
sweat flying instead of wings.
何にこだわればいいの
What should I cling to?
愛の見えない 時代の恋人達ね
We're lovers in an era where love's nowhere to be seen.
まっさかさまに堕ちて desire
Falling head over heels, desire,
炎のように燃えて desire
burning like a blazing fire, desire.
恋も dance, dance, dance, dance ほど
Not being able to dance, dance, dance, dance
夢中になれない なんてね 淋しい
my way into losing myself in love makes me feel so lonely.
Get up, Get up, Get up, Get up Burning heart
腕を離してよ
Let go of my arm.
キスをされるのも ごめん
Sorry, I don't want to be kissed either.
気分じゃないの
I'm not in the mood.
ヒールを脱ぎ捨て 感じているのよ
I kick my heels off and feel...
夜の孤独な長さ
...just how long and lonely the night is.
そう 多分 贅沢な悩み
Yeah, I know this might be a lavish concern,
分かっているわ これでも
but even so, I know...
何を信じればいいのスキャンダルさえ
What should I believe in? Even scandals...
時代のエクスタシよ
...are the ecstasies of the times.
ぶつかり合って廻れ desire
Bump into me and then turn, desire,
星のかけらを掴め desire
catch a piece of broken star, desire.
夢はそうよ 見る前に醒めてしまったら
If you wake up before you dream,
何にもならない
it amounts to nothing.
Get up, Get up, Get up, Get up Burning love
まっさかさまに堕ちて desire
Falling head over heels, desire,
炎のように燃えて desire
burning like a blazing fire, desire.
恋も dance, dance, dance, dance ほど
Not being able to dance, dance, dance, dance
夢中になれない なんてね 淋しい
my way into losing myself in love makes me feel so lonely.
Get up, Get up, Get up, Get up Burning heart
Get up, Get up, Get up, Get up
Get up, Get up, Get up, Get up Burning love
宝鐘マリン、常闇トワで「DESIRE -情熱-」でした。
That was "DESIRE" by Houshou Marine and Tokoyami Towa.
はい、すごくパワフルな雰囲気で素晴らしかったですですね。
Yeah, it had a super powerful vibe and was amazing.
そうですね、迫力がありましたね。
Indeed, it had a lot of impact.
えー今回ですね、このトワさんとこの中森明菜さんへのシナジーがすごくて
And this time, the synergy between Towa-san and Akina Nakamori is amazing,
マリンさんはこの歌お箱だったらしいんですけど、少し食われてしまったというお話で
and apparently Marine-san used to be great at this song, but she got a bit overshadowed.
はい、食われてましたね。
Yeah, you were definitely overshadowed.
食われてしまったといえば、そういえば一つ情報があるんですけども、最近宝鐘マリンさんがハマっている食べ物があるそうで。
Speaking of being overshadowed, I actually have a piece of news: Marine-san apparently has a new favorite food lately.
マイブーム？はい、しらすだそうです。
Your current obsession? Yes, shirasu (whitebait).
生しらすの方ですかね？
Raw whitebait, is it?
ちょっとそこまでは聞いてなかったので
I didn't hear about that specific detail,
終わったと聞こうと思います。それでは次の曲へまいりましょう、どうぞ。
so I'll have to ask later. Let's move on to the next song, please.
初恋の味はレモンのようにすっぱいそうですが、キスの味もすっぱい...それでは聞いていただきましょう、初恋。
They say first love tastes sour like lemon, and so does a kiss... Let's listen to "First Love".
五月雨は緑色 悲しくさせたよ 一人の午後は
The early summer rain was green, making me sad on a lonely afternoon.
恋をして淋しくて 届かぬ想いを温めていた
I fell in love and felt so alone, warming feelings that could never reach you.
好きと言えずに 初恋は ふりこ細工の心
Unable to say "I love you," my first love was a pendulum-like heart.
放課後の校庭を 走る君がいた 遠くで僕はいつでも君を探していた
You were running across the schoolyard after class; from afar, I was always searching for you.
好きだと言えずに 初恋は
Unable to say "I like you," my first love
ふりこ細工の心
Was a heart like a delicate pendulum
放課後の校庭を走る君がいた
After school, you were there running across the yard
遠くで僕は いつでも君を探してた
From afar, I was always searching for you
浅い夢だから 胸をはなれない
Because it was a fleeting dream, it won't leave my heart
夕映えはあんず色
The evening glow was apricot-colored
帰り道 一人 口笛吹いて
On the way home, I whistled alone
名前さえ呼べなくて
I couldn’t even call your name
とらわれた心 見つめていたよ
I just stared at my captive heart
好きだと言えずに 初恋は
Unable to say "I like you," my first love
ふりこ細工の心
Was a heart like a delicate pendulum
風に舞った花びらが 水面を乱すように
Like petals dancing in the wind, disturbing the water's surface
愛という字書いてみては 震えてたあの頃
Writing the character for "love," my hands trembling in those days
浅い夢だから 胸をはなれない
Because it was a fleeting dream, it won't leave my heart
放課後の校庭を 走る君がいた
After school, you were there running across the yard
遠くで僕は いつでも君を探してた
From afar, I was always searching for you
浅い夢だから 胸をはなれない
Because it was a fleeting dream, it won't leave my heart
胸をはなれない
It won't leave my heart
宝鐘マリン、大空スバルで初恋でした。
Houshou Marine and Oozora Subaru performing "Hatsukoi."
いや、とても甘酸っぱい雰囲気でしたね。
Man, that had a very bittersweet vibe to it.
そうですね。こちらは企画のマールちゃんとスーくんから来て るそうですね。
Indeed. This comes from project planning Ma-chan and Su-kun, apparently.
なるほど。その企画の中で幼なじみの設定をそのまま曲のコラボで使ったということですね。
I see. So they used the childhood friend setting from that project directly for this song collaboration.
そうですね。
That's right.
はい。
Yes.
ちなみに何かこう甘酸っぱい記憶ってありますか?
By the way, do you have any bittersweet memories like that?
あの、学校帰りにハイチュウを食べた時が一番酸っぱかったですね。
Um, eating Hi-Chew on the way home from school was the most sour one.
甘酸っぱいですね。
That's "sweet and sour" alright.
そうですね。
Indeed.
それでは次の曲にまいりましょう。どうぞ。
Now then, let's move on to the next song. Here we go.
アーユーレディー? イエーイ!
Are you ready? Yeah!
ヘイヘイヘイヘイヘイ
Hey hey hey hey hey
あいつもこいつもおの席をただ一つ狙っているんだよ
This guy and that guy too are aiming for that one seat
このクラスで一番の美人の隣を
It’s the one next to the prettiest girl in class
あーみんなライバルさ
Ah, everyone’s a rival
あーいのちがけだよ
Ah, it’s a desperate predicament
運命の女神さまよこのぼくにほほんで一度だけでも
Oh, the goddess of destiny, please bless me with your smile even if it’s just once
勉強する気もしない気もこの時にかかっているんだよ
Whether I feel like studying or not all depends on this very moment
もし駄目ならこのぼくはもうグレちまうよ
If you don’t approve of me, then I’ll go ahead and become a delinquent
Are you ready?
(yeah!)
Hey hey hey hey hey
Yeah!
あいつもこいつもあの席を
This guy and that guy too
ただ一つねらっているんだよ
Are all aiming for that single seat
このクラスで一番の美人の隣を
The seat next to the prettiest girl in the class
あーあ みんなライバルさ
Ah, everyone's a rival
あーあ いのちがけだよ
Ah, it's a desperate struggle
(woo) yeah yeah yeah
運命の女神様よ
Oh, goddess of destiny
このぼくによいほうえんで
Please smile upon me just once
このぼくにしあわせを与えておくれ
Please grant me happiness,
勉強する気もしない気もこのときにかかっているんだよ
Whether I study or not all depends on this moment!
もし駄目ならこのぼくはもうグレちまうよ
If it fails, I'll just become a delinquent!
Hey hey hey hey hey
宝鐘マリン、犬神ころね、白銀ノエル、雪花ラミィ
Houshou Marine, Inugami Korone, Shirogane Noel, and Yukihana Lamy
で、学園天国でした。
performed "Gakuen Tengoku"!
元気いっぱい歌っていただきましたね。
They sang it with so much energy!
そうですね、邪神なのか神なのかわからないですけども。
That's right, though I'm not sure if it's demonic or divine.
ちょっと意味が重複してますね、失礼いたしました。はい、というわけで
That's a bit redundant, my apologies. Anyway—
ラミィさんのですね、歌唱がすごくあの、高い声が出ていてね。
Lamy's vocals had such high notes coming out!
高音出てましたね。はい、すごくあの、良かったですね。
High notes indeed. Yes, it was really great.
すごくよかったですね。はい。そしてころねさんのタップダンス。
Really great. Yes. And Korone's tap dance!
いやあれすごいですね。足が5、6本に見えましたけど。
Man, that was amazing. It looked like she had 5 or 6 legs!
すごくいっぱい見えましたね。そうですね、はい。
She looked like she had so many. That's right, yes.
そしてここでノエルさんが登場と。ついにやってきましたね。
And here Noel makes her appearance. Finally arrived!
この後もまだ白銀ノエルさんは出演を控えてるとか。あ、楽しみですね。
Shirogane Noel still has upcoming appearances after this. Oh, how exciting.
楽しみですね。はい。それではこのあと、夏の海をテーマにした曲を
Exciting indeed. Yes. Well then, next up, we'll deliver three songs
3曲連続でお送りいたします。もう秋なんですけどね。
in a row with the theme of the summer ocean. Even though it's already autumn,
残暑ですかね。まだ暑い日が続いております。はい。
I guess it's late summer heat. Hot days are still continuing. Yes.
チュウ チュー チューチュー 夏のお嬢さん
Chu-chu-chu-chu, summer young lady,
ビキニ が とっても 似合う よ しげき的 さ クラクラ しちゃう
Your bikini suits you so well, the stimulation makes me dizzy!
チュウ チュー チューチュー 潮 風 を すりぬけ スケートボード に のって むかえ に 行く 待って て おくれ
Chu-chu-chu-chu, slipping through the sea breeze, riding a skateboard to go greet you, wait for me!
君 は 僕 の あこがれ の 人 だ よ
You are the person I adore!
アイスクリーム ユースクリーム 恋する 季節
Ice cream, you scream, season of love!
ビーチ・パラソル ひくく し て かくれる よ
Lowering the beach parasol, hiding away,
アイスクリーム ユースクリーム 好き さ
Ice cream, you scream, I love you!
お嬢さん お嬢さん
Young lady, young lady!
チュウ チュー チューチュー 夏のお嬢さん
Chu-chu-chu-chu, summer young lady,
浜辺 の 人気 さらって とんで いる ん だ ね ヤキモキ し ちゃう
Stealing all the attention on the beach, making me anxious!
チュウ チュー チューチュー 波 のり を する なら 君 の 似顔絵 かいた サーフボード かして あげる よ
Chu-chu-chu-chu, if you're going surfing, I'll lend you a surfboard with your portrait drawn on it!
僕 は 君 に 首ったけ な ん だ よ
I'm completely head over heels for you!
アイスクリーム ユースクリーム 恋する 季節
Ice cream, you scream, season of love!
砂 に 書い た よ テレ ながら ラブレター
Written in the sand, shyly, a love letter!
アイスクリーム ユースクリーム 好き さ
Ice cream, you scream, I love you!
お嬢さん お嬢さん
Young lady, young lady!
僕 は 君 に 首ったけ な ん だ よ
I'm completely head over heels for you!
アイスクリーム ユースクリーム 恋する 季節
Ice cream, you scream, season of love!
砂 に 書い た よ テレ ながら ラブレター
Written in the sand, shyly, a love letter!
アイスクリーム...
Ice cream...
アイスクリーム ユースクリーム 好きさ
Ice cream, youth cream, I love it!
お嬢さん お嬢さん
Young lady, young lady
アアア アアア…
Ah, ah...
渚のシンドバッド
Nagisa no Sindbad
ここかと思えば またまたあちら
Just when I think you're here, you're somewhere else again
浮気なひとね
You're such a fickle guy
サーフィンボード 小わきにかかえ 美女から美女へ
Carrying a surfboard under your arm, going from beauty to beauty
ビキニがとってもお似合いですと
"You look great in that bikini," you say,
肩など抱いて
putting your arm around my shoulder,
ちょいとおにいさん なれなれしいわ
Hold on, mister, you're being a bit too familiar!
くちびる盗む早わざは
Your quick moves to steal a kiss,
うわさ通りだわ あなたシンドバッド
just as the rumors say—you're my Sindbad!
セクシー あなたはセクシー
Sexy, you're so sexy,
私はいちころで ダウンよ
I'm knocked out in a single blow,
もうあなたにあなたにおぼれる
drowning completely, head over heels in you!
波乗りあざやか 拍手を浴びて キスの嵐
Catching waves cleanly amid applause, a storm of kisses
あちらのパラソル こちらのパラソル ウィンク投げて
Winking at parasols left and right
夜ふけになったら あなたの部屋へ しのんで行くよ
I'll sneak into your room when it gets late
ちょいとおにいさん いい気なものね
Hold on, mister, you're having it too good!
うっとりさせる テクニック
That mesmerizing technique of yours
腹が立つほどよ あなたシンドバッド
makes me so mad—you're my Sindbad!
セクシー あなたはセクシー
Sexy, you're so sexy,
私はいちころで ダウンよ
I'm knocked out in a single blow,
もうあなたにあなたにおぼれる
drowning completely, head over heels in you!
青い水平線を いま駆け抜けてく
Running past the blue horizon now
とぎすまされた 時の流れ感じて
Keenly feeling the sharpened flow of time
AH ときめきへと 動き出す世界は
Ah, the world begins to move toward excitement
忘れかけてた 遠い夢の訪れ
Like the arrival of a distant, forgotten dream
RIDE ON TIME さまよう想いなら やさしく受け止めて そっと包んで
Ride on time, if my thoughts are wandering, catch them gently and wrap them softly
RIDE ON TIME 心に火を点けて あふれる喜びに向かって RIDE ON TIME
Ride on time, light a fire in my heart, toward overflowing joy, ride on time
僕の輝く未来 さあ回り始めて
My shining future, come on, start revolving
虚ろな日々も 全て愛に溶け込む
Even hollow days all melt away into love
AH 何という朝 今すぐ君のもと 届けに行こう 燃える心迷わズ
Ah, what a morning! Let's go deliver this burning heart to you right now without hesitation
RIDE ON TIME 時よ走り出せ 愛よ光り出せ 目もくらむ程
Ride on time, time, start running! Love, start shining so bright it blinds the eyes!
RIDE ON TIME 時よ走り出せ
Ride on time, time, take off running!
愛よ光り出せ 目もくらむ程
Love, shine so bright it blinds me!
RIDE ON TIME 心に火を点けて
Ride on time, light a fire in your heart,
飛び立つ魂に送るよ RIDE ON TIME
sending it to your soaring soul, ride on time!
届けに行こう 燃える心今こそ
Let's go deliver this burning heart right now!
RIDE ON TIME 時よ走り出せ
Ride on time, time, take off running!
愛よ光り出せ 目もくらむ程
Love, shine so bright it blinds me!
RIDE ON TIME 心に火を点けて
Ride on time, light a fire in your heart,
飛び立つ魂に送るよ RIDE ON TIME
sending it to your soaring soul, ride on time!
RIDE ON TIME さまよう想いなら
Ride on time, if your thoughts are wandering,
やさしく受け止めて そっと包んで
gently catch them and softly wrap them up.
RIDE ON TIME 心に火を点けて
Ride on time, light a fire in your heart,
あふれる喜びに拡がれ RIDE ON TIME
spreading into overflowing joy, ride on time!
RIDE ON TIME 時よ走り出せ
Ride on time, time, take off running!
愛よ光り出せ 目もくらむ程
Love, shine so bright it blinds me!
RIDE ON TIME 心に火を点けて
Ride on time, light a fire in your heart,
飛び立つ魂に送るよ RIDE ON TIME
sending it to your soaring soul, ride on time!
宝鐘マリン みなとあくあで夏の お嬢さん
Houshou Marine and Minato Aqua with "Summer Young Lady."
兎田ぺこら イナニスでなぎさのシンドバッド ガウルグラでRIDE ON TIMEでした
Usada Pekora, Ina'nis with "Nagisa no Sinbad," and Gura with "Ride on Time."
とっても可愛らしい3曲で夏らしかったですね
Those three very cute summer songs were so summery, weren't they?
そうですね まだまだ夏は続いていきそうです
That's right, summer seems like it's going to keep going.
みなとあくあさんのダンスがすごく可愛らしくて目に入りましたね
Minato Aqua-san's dance was super cute and really caught my eye.
いやいいですね 夏のお嬢さんと夏のお母さんでしたね 親子での共演でした
Yeah, it was great. Summer young lady and summer mother—a parent-child collaboration!
アクアさんのお母さんはマリンさんですからね そうですね
Aqua-san's mother is Marine-san, after all. That's right.
そして兎田のシンドバッド こちらはイナニスさんが初めてこの歌を歌うのにとても練習してくださったそうで
And Usada's "Sinbad," apparently Ina'nis-san practiced really hard since it was her first time singing this song.
すごくお上手でしたね 日本語ですごく上手に歌っていただきました
She was so good! She sang it in Japanese so wonderfully.
とても可愛らしかったです
It was very cute.
そしてRIDE ON TIME こちらはグラさんの大得意なおハコの曲ですね
And "Ride on Time," that's Gura-san's absolute specialty, her signature song, right?
そうですね とても歌枠とかでも聞いております
That's right, I've heard it on stream and stuff too.
というわけで お次の曲なんですが
So, moving on to our next song...
その前に なんと緊急情報で マリンさんの髪が
Before that, we have breaking news—Marine's hair...
新しく 新しく追加されるんですか? そのようです
is newly being added? It seems so!
なんと それはとても楽しみですね ちょっと楽しみにしておきましょう
Wow, that's something to really look forward to. Let's look forward to it!
そして 最後の曲となります もう最後ですか
And now, it's time for our final song. Already the last one?
そうなんです あっという間ですね お時間は 寂しいですね
That's right. Time flies, doesn't it? How time flies, it's sad.
それでは最後の曲 参りましょう なんてったってアイドル どうぞ
Well then, let's head to our final song: "Nantettatte Idol." Here we go!
なんてったって アイドル
After all, I'm an idol!
なんてったってアイドル
[Song: Nantettatte Idol]
赤いコンバーチブルから
From a red convertible
ドアをあけずに飛びおりて
Jumping out without opening the door
ミニのスカートひらりで
With my mini skirt fluttering
男の子達の視線を釘づけ
Nailing all the boys' gazes
黒いサングラスかけても
Even if I wear dark sunglasses
プライバシーをかくしても
And hide my privacy
ちょっとくらいは誰かに
Just a little bit to someone
そうよ私だと気づかなくちゃイヤ・イヤ
You've gotta realize it's me, no no!
恋をするにはするけど
I mean, I do fall in love, but
スキャンダルならノーサンキュー
Scandals? No thank you!
イメージが大切よ
Image is everything
清く正しく美しく
Pure, righteous, and beautiful
なんてったってアイドル
After all, I'm an idol
私はアイドル
I'm an idol
You're an idol
なんてったってアイドル
After all, I'm an idol
ステキなアイドル
A wonderful idol
You're an idol
アイドルはやめられない
I can't stop being an idol
Yeah! Yeah! Yeah!
なんてったってアイドル...
After all, I'm an idol...
Yeah! Yeah! Yeah!
ちょっといかしたタイプの
A somewhat cool type of
ミュージシャンとつき合っても
Even if I date a musician
知らぬ存ぜぬととぼけて
Playing dumb like I know nothing
レポータ達をけむに巻いちゃうわ
I'll hoodwink the reporters
ずっとこのままでいたい
I want to stay like this forever
年なんかはとりたくない
I don't want to get older
いつもみんなにキャー・キャー言われ続けたい 楽しければいい
I want everyone to keep screaming for me, as long as it's fun
恋をするにはするけど
I mean, I do fall in love, but
インタビューならノーコメント
No comment for interviews
マネージャーをとおして
Through the manager
清く正しく美しく
Pure, righteous, and beautiful
なんてったってアイドル
After all, I'm an idol
このままアイドル
An idol just like this
You're an idol
なんてったってアイドル
After all, I'm an idol
いつでもアイドル
Always an idol
You're an idol
アイドルはやめられない
I can't stop being an idol
Yeah! Yeah! Yeah!
なんてったってアイドル...
After all, I'm an idol...
Yeah! Yeah! Yeah!
万歳！
Banzai!
ほうしょうマリン、うさだぺこら、しらぬいフレア、しろがねのえるのホロライブ３期生でなんてったってアイドルでした！
That was "Nantettatte Idol" by Hololive 3rd Gen!
いや、とってもアイドルしてましたね！プリプリでしたね！
Man, you guys were total idols! So perky!
プリプリでしたね！かわいいかったです。
So perky! It was super cute.
かわいいかったです。
Super cute.
しろがねのえるさんは２回でてましたね！あ、そうですね！
Shirogane Noel-san appeared twice, didn't she? Ah, that's right!
あ、今回のキャスティングはちょっと２回はミスったみたいです。あー、なるほどね、そう言ってましたね。そうですね、はい。
Ah, it seems like there was a little mistake in the casting doing it twice. Ah, I see, you said that. That's right, yes.
新しい髪型もよかったですね！すごくね、あの、かわいらしかったですね。そうですね、はい。
The new hairstyles were great too! Super cute, right? That's right, yes.
こちら、あの、じつは案としてい、はい、ポニーテールもよかったんですけども、あと赤澤あいせいがラフのじかん、ラフの時点で、はい、もひかんを提案していたそうでで、もひかんですか？そうでした、新髪型にもひかんを
Actually, as an idea for this—yeah, ponytails were nice, but also Akasawa-sensei proposed a mohawk at the rough sketch stage. A mohawk? That's right, a mohawk for the new hairstyle—
そんなの！あ、やめるんだ！ちょっと、ちょ、ちょ、さっきからね、聞いてれば、わけのわからないごじょー、からだがすならやめてくださいよ！
No way! Ah, stop it! Wait, wait, wait, from earlier, if you're going to talk nonsense about my body, please stop!
本当だと思ってたんですけどね！ちょっと、そのキャラやめろもう！
I thought it was real! Hey, drop that character already!
ねぇ、そのキャラやめて！そのキャラでやれって言ったのよあんた！いやいや、そんな、やれって言ったら覚えたの！覚えたの！もういいです、もういいです！
Hey, drop that character! You're the one who told me to do that character! No way, you said to do it, so I learned it! I learned it! Okay, that's enough, that's enough!
やっぱりいつも通りね、戻ってまいりました！はい！
As expected, we're back to our usual selves! Yes!
ふぶきちゃんとね、よせんぱい、や本当に今回MCありがとうございました！ありがとうございました！すごい絶妙なMCの空気が
Fubuki-chan, Senpai, thank you so much for MCing this time! Thank you very much! Such an exquisite MC atmosphere...
なぞでしたね
It was a mystery, huh?
絶妙でしたね
It was exquisite, huh?
ホロミ不ざいの空気ですごいモヤモヤしましたね
The air in Holomi's absence made me feel so hazy.
あの、あそこだ
Um, right there.
あ、言わないでよ
Ah, don't say it!
モヤモヤしちゃった
I got all hazy.
ところで、ところで、これ
By the way, by the way, this...
髪型ちょっとどうかな？
How's this hairstyle?
あ、可愛い！
Ah, cute!
可愛いかな、どうどう？
Is it cute? How's that?
って言うね、やっぱいいね
You say that, it really is nice.
うん、いいね
Yeah, it's nice.
もう1個さ、もう1個気づくことない？
Isn't there something else you noticed?
気づくこと？
Something I noticed?
なんだろなんだろ
I wonder what it is.
情報は髪型だけではなかった
The info wasn't just about the hairstyle.
あ、おっ！
Ah, oh!
イヤリングが
The earrings...
ついてる！
They're on!
気づいちゃった！
You noticed!
何柄だ、何柄だ？
What pattern is this?
ちょっと、見えてる？
Wait, can you see it?
どう？
How is it?
あ、ほんとだ
Ah, really!
あ、ハートのね
Ah, heart-shaped...
ハートのイヤリング！
Heart earrings!
つけてる！
You're wearing them!
え、これ可愛い！
Eh, these are cute!
めっちゃ可愛い！
Super cute!
また、また見て
Look again, look again.
え、後ろ、後ろの姿
Eh, the back, the back view.
後ろ姿、あー
The back view, ahh.
いいね
Nice!
後ろ、後ろも見てね！
Look at the back too!
あ、見えなくなっちゃった
Ah, I can't see it anymore.
というわけで、それはですね
So anyway...
お時間がやってまいりました
The time has come.
振り返っちゃおうかな
Let's look back, huh?
あっという間の時間でございました
It was a flash of time.
この時間はあっという間ですね
This time passes in a flash, huh?
はい、ホロライブ昭和歌謡祭終了のお時間でございます
Yes, it is time for the hololive Shouwa Kayou Festival.
ここまでご視聴くださった
To everyone who watched until here,
皆さんがどうもありがとうございました
thank you all so much.
ありがとうございました
Thank you very much!
また次回の日曜祭でお会いいたしましょう
Let's meet again at the next Kayou Festival.
はい、ありがとうございました
Yes, thank you very much!
それではさようなら
Well then, goodbye!
さようなら
Goodbye!
ちょっと待って、いけないで
Wait a minute, don't go yet!
まだ紹介したいものがある
There's still something I want to introduce.
ちょっと、この新しいお目見え、まだバイバイじゃないから
Wait, it's not bye-bye yet, so...
ちょっと、まだ紹介が
Wait, the introduction is still...
あ、グッズが、ちょっと
Ah, the goods!
君たち！
You guys!
昭和歌謡祭どうでしたか？
How was the Shouwa Kayou Festival?
楽しんでいただけたでしょうか？
Did you enjoy it?
ぜひ最後まで聞いていってくださいね！
Please listen until the end!
宝鐘マリン活動3周年記念グッズです！
Houshou Marine's 3rd Anniversary goods!
船長と宅飲みアクリルジオラマスタンドです！
The Captain & Drinking Acrylic Diorama Stand!
お母様のあかさあい先生描きおろしです！
Illustrated by mama Akasa Ai!
君と宅飲みしているマリンというコンセプトなんですが
The concept is Marine having a drink with you,
そしたらこのマリンと一緒に飲みたいですよね！
so you'd want to drink together with this Marine!
船長描きおろしコースターです！
The Captain-illustrated coaster!
どんなに可愛くても容赦なく上にグラスをのせてください！
Mercilessly place your glass on top!
いやー、でもグラスがないよなー
Man, but I don't have a glass...
ドクロくん盃です！
The Dokuro-kun sake cup!
ついにでたかって感じですよね！
Feels like it's finally here!
一緒にドクロくんで乾杯しようや！
Let's toast together with Dokuro-kun!
まあこれで3つは欲しいな！
I'd want three of these!
海賊船プレート！
Pirate ship plate!
この船はなんだってのせるぜ！
This ship will carry anything!
すべてのセットをご購入いただけましたらば
If you purchase the complete set,
数量限定直筆メッセージ入りポストカードと音声がついてきます！
you'll get a limited postcard and voice!
複製メッセージバージョンもあるので安心です！
There's a replicated version, so rest assured!
今回はね、宅飲みセットなコンセプトでした！
The concept was a drinking-at-home set!
22時から販売開始です！
Sales start at 22:00!
ぜひぜひゲットしてくださいね！
Please get it!
そして、超絶朗報です！
And, extraordinarily great news!
船長描きおろしのLINEスタンプ
Captain-illustrated LINE stickers,
このあと22時頃から販売開始です！
sales start around 22:00!
本当に君たち全員使ってくれないと普通に発狂しそう！
I'd go crazy if you don't all use them!
徹夜で描きちらかしたから、絶対ゲットしてくださいね！
I scribbled them through the night, so get them!
見てくれてありがとうございました！
Thank you for watching!
4年目も船長についてきてくださいね！
Please keep following the Captain into year 4!
それではいきますよ！しゅこー！
Now then, here we go! Shuukou!